ILGWU Justice Photographs 5780/102 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Southeast Region (Box 23, Folder 14)
  Includes: ILGers distributing leaflets outside Rich's Department Store in Atlanta, GA; Higher Department Store in Cleveland, R.H. Stearns in Boston and Hess' Department Store in Allentown, PA- 4/15/62; Jerry Levine, Al Gross, President B.O. Young, Mayor William B. Hartsfield sign proclamations that make September 4-10 Union Label Week in Atlanta- 9/1/62; Southeast Region Business Agent Benny Dansavage and Arthur Mason and Ike York lead workers in strike against Oneita Knit in Andrews, South Carolina- 8/1/63; Miami Local 415 demonstrate- 8/15/63; ILGers and South Carolina state labor leaders are outside governor's office to talk to him about strike on Oneita Knit with Nick Bonanno, E.T. Kirkland- state AFL-CIO secretary-treasurer, Wayne Dernacourt- TWVA representative, Mac Rose, AFL-CIO COPE representative, Leroy Crane- president Local 371, Sinway Young- president state AFL-CIO, Mary Cameron- Local 371 business agent, Hazel McLaurin- chairlady, Hazel Brantley, Peggy Swails, Louise Wheeler, Mary Altman, Vincent Payne, and Judy Ackerman- 9/1/63; strikers at Oneita Knitting Mills in Andrews South Carolina hold strike pay checks- 1/15/64; Local 371 executive board members with business agent Mary Cameron and organizer Horace Boan- 3/15/64; installation of newly elected officers area locals in Columbia, SC with Mary Cameron- business agent, Martin Morand- regional director, Sinway Young and E.T. Kirkland- 5/1/564; worker asks Local 378 president Maruella Shoddy for another leaflet to hand out outside G.C. plant in Town Creek, AL- 7/15/65; ILGers conduct intensive telephone campaign for Tobacco Worker's Union- 6/15/65; ILGers in NY picket Alba-Waldensian, Inc. at Empire State Building; picket woman and three children outside Kayser-Roth-Local 457-6/15/59; ILGer Bonnie Justice of Greenville, SC holds up ILGWU publication at Southeast Regional Conference in Atlanta, GA- 10/1/65; Randi Roberto workers Algeria Vasquez and Evis Ramirez initiate picket- 10/1/65; Executive Board members of Southeast Local 534 of Lake City, South Carolina celebrate birthdays of Era Strokes- chairlady and Mary Cameron- South Carolina director- 11/1/65; contract terms are spelled out for employees of Brookfield Mills of Sanford, FL by Bill Krost- business agent, Alix Scheinman- firm's general manager, Rosa Holloway- member of negotiation committee, George Castelli- shop manager, Helen Kailin and Rose Clark- chairlady and Dorothy Brown, and Robert Gladnick- Miami manager- 11/15/65; members who helped organize the Cherokee Plant- Clayton Fox, Jean Moser, Hellen Webb, Johnnie Helms, Pearl Prince, David Russell and Bill Moore- 12/15/65; a motorcade in Madisonville, TN to mobilize Cherokee sportswear- 12/15/65
- Southeast Region (Box 23, Folder 15)
  Includes: picket of Kayper Roth; Eva Day of Southeast Region Local 523, Business Agent Morton Shapiro, Congress Graham Barden, Mamie Skarren discuss legislation- 2/1/60; two picketers outside Elberton Manufacturing co.- 3/1/60; Elberton strikers picket Rilla Mfg. Co. (subsidy of Elberton)- 3/1/60; workers in Elberton, GA ratify agreement with Rhoda Lee Blouses, lead by Regional Director E.T. Kehrer- 3/15/60; director E.T. Kehrer talks to active ILGers- 10/15/60; ILGWU Secretary- Treasurer Louis Stulberg addresses 23rd Conference of Southeast Region in Atlanta, GA- w/ E.T. Kehrer- 7/1561; at local 475's annual banquet in Cullman, AL- Rep. Carl Elliot, former Alabama governor James Folsom and wife, Inez Wesson, and Roy Samples- head of local 457- 1/1/62; Jerry Levine, Al Gross- local 122 business agent, Bo Young- President Local 95, Mayor William B. Hartsfield, Bill Crim- Secretary-Treasurer, Georgia AFL-CIO, Joe Jacobs, J.O. Moore president Atlanta Labor Council- 9/15/61; ILGers picket Judy Bond affiliates in Spartanburg, SC and Birmingham, AL- 2/1/62; Local 122 distributors leaflets against Rhoda Lee in Atlanta- 3/15/63; Spartanburg Local 581 picket Greenwood Shirt Company in SC- 4/1/62
- Southeast Region (Box 23, Folder 16)
  Includes: Local 570 of Sanford, Florida let servicemen know they are remembered at Christmas time- Rose Clark- chairlady, Mary Inflow, Maine Joe Cate, Bonnie Campbell, Eula Cornelius, Cathie Brooks- 1/1/66; G.G. Lingerie meets with business agent Ed Sharp and Ben Dansavage- 5/1/66; Margaret Hodges gives testimony before Paul Weil on ULP's committed by Marlene Industries- 5/1/66; Southeast Region Director Martin Morand negotiates with Lena Young, Maggie Purser, Mary Johns, Irma Long, Leona Fountain- 5/1/66; ILGWU negotiating teams of Andrews knit- Winnie Cunningham, Frances Appleby, Ruth Sullivan, Ben Dansavage, Ola Mae Cork, Ed Sharp, Dorothy Tucker, Russel McMahon, and Syble Neal- 1966; President Louis Stulberg addresses delegates at Southeast Region Conference- 6/1/5/66; workers of Coed Collar Co in Tuscaloosa, AL sign in for picket duty with organizer Russ McMahan and Margie Coburn- 8/1/66; lady picketing Coed Collar Co.; workers of Munsingwear Corporation in Memphis petitioned for an election- with Mason London, Chester Moore, Bobbie Dyson, Timothy Mull, Verdi Phelps, Clint Combs, Fannie Bryant, Pat Kennedy, Jim Avery, Charlie Jones, Charles Rice, and Edith Covington- 8/15/66; Rev. Peter Clark gives labor day mass in South Carolina at St. Peter's Catholic Church- 9/15/66 workers picket McKay-10/15/66; Local 480 of Tuscaloosa, AL receive charter from Business Agent Ben Dansavage with Syble Neal, Ola Mae Cork, Eleanor Rumsey, Frances Appleby, and Ruth Sullivan- 11/15/66; North Carolina District Council organizes itself with Janet Bush, Thomasina Boone, Clarence Lufton, Joyce Ross, Jesse Riddle, Ethel Vick and Julia Newsome- 1/15/67; workers at G. Gertz Enterprises sign authorization cards with Juan Lozano looking on 2/15/67; President Louis Stulberg administers oath to Harry Metz for manager of Local 415 and 475, with Nancy Brown- president local 475 and Martin Morand- director Southeast Region- 2/15/67; strikers of Smart Miss and McKay of Miami picket in front of DiLido Hotel in Miami Beach- Buena Banks, Minnie Cadick, Sylvia Connelly and Adele Burgese- 4/1/67; ILGWU general organizer Maida Springer with employee's from Brookfield Mfg. Co.- 5/1/67; officers of Local 308 at E-Z Mills in Cartersville, GA take oath- E.B. Keys- local president, Claude Garland- VP, Kathryn Martin- secretary-treasurer, Mamie Martin- recording secretary, Leona Craig- shop chairlady- 5/1/67; Kate Lewis representing Florence, SC Local 366 speaks at Southeast meeting- 6/15/67; Delegate Cletus Warmath reports on activities of Southeast Local 496 from Jackson, TN- 6/15/67; workshop at Southeast Region's conference in Daytona Beach, FL- 6/15/67; members of locals in Alabama and TN with Southeast Region organizers- 8/1/67;; ILGers in North Carolina at educational program launched by North Carolina District Council- 12/1/67; pickets at Wentworth Manufacturing Co.- 9/15/68; workers at International Outerwear in Clarkesville, GA raise hands in agreement over contract- 2/15/68
- Street Photographs (Box 23, Folder 17)
  Includes: black man moving garment rack, man moves boxes in snow, black man rest after moving, man moving stack of boxes
- Strikes (Box 23, Folder 18)
  Includes: announcement of dressmakers general strike- 1968; man with empty rack- not delivering dresses; Los Angeles Sportswear Strike- 1941- workers wear sashes and hold pickets; women organizing outside Regent Corset, Co.; portrait of a woman picketing; strike against Marlene industry; picket line that runs the length of a block; strikers in 1971; black women picket in snow; a woman pickets while police look on
- Strikes (Box 23, Folder 19)
  Includes: people picketing Norma Kamali, Inc.- includes a black and Hispanic woman
- Strikes (Box 23, Folder 20)
  Includes: 2 men picketing East End Sportswear, Inc.
- Triangle Fire Photographs digital photos (Box 23, Folder 21)
  Includes: people gathered around monument dedicated to unidentified victim of fire; mourning procession after the fire; negatives
- Union Health Center (Box 23, Folder 22)
  Includes: West German Labor and Social Affairs Minister Herbert Ehrenberg uses treadmill in union health center- 1/15/79; portrait of Administrator Milton Arons- 7/1/7; administrative director of Union Health Center Sol Bieger reviews operations with department supervisors- 11/15/77; gynecology department of union health center; member of Local 23-25 takes tonometer test; patients in waiting room of clinic- 11/79; Working Women's Conference conducted by Union Health Center Social Service Program- 6/80; at end of Social Services Conference members children singing union label song- 5/81; members take notes during Union Health Center Social Services Department- 5/81; staffers of Union Health Center receive CPR training- with Health Center Administrative Director Solomon Berger, Barbara Flanagan hold certificate awarded by Safety Services Director John LaCaribba-5/81; portrait of union health center, portrait of George M. Price, M.D.- director of union health center; DD and LBJ and VP Hubert Humphrey at 50th Anniversary
- Union Health Center (Box 23, Folder 23)
  Includes: union health center 50th Anniversary logo; black doctor looking through microscope; older woman receives x-rays; Asian man receives X- Ray; woman visits gynecologist; man running on treadmill, Asian woman doctor handles blood; blood bank program is at center; blood driver at Local 225 and 275; woman taking blood pressure; health educator Karen Openstein explains high blood pressure to Local 66-40 members at M.J. Creations in NY- with Irving Bakal assistant manager and Claudette Paul- interpreter- 4/85; ILGer Pauline Newman- education director of Union Health Center on TV- 9/15/76
- Union Health Center (Box 23, Folder 24)
  Includes: pulmonary function analysis; ILGers display some of the health care postcards that were delivered to the White House 4/85; ILGers holding signs at a parade- includes black women
- Union Health Center - NY (Box 23, Folder 25)
  Includes: eye examination at center; doctor analyzes blood, patient receives x-ray; workers in record room; black man doctor operating machine; doctor taking blood pressure; pharmacist pouring medicine; woman sewing
- Union Health Center - Stock Photos (Box 24, Folder 1)
  Includes: patients in waiting room and patients registering; black woman nurse gives man an EKG; woman doctor draws blood; pharmacist in his work area; staff dinner in 1921; portrait of a medal that signifies commencement of health center; worker getting medical results, nurse drawing blood, hearing test; pharmacist working, 50th Anniversary medal, nurse supporting a patient's neck
- Union Label digital photos (Box 24, Folder 2)
  Includes: models wearing union-made clothes during ILGWU fashion show at AFL-CIO convention- 11/17/81; Eleanor Roosevelt sews in first union label in 1950s; Mrs. May Rockefeller sewing first label- 1950's
- Union Label Department (Box 24, Folder 3)
  Includes: President Eisenhower with President George Meany and William Schnitzler tour exhibit; AFL-CIO union industries show dies and podium; model ILGWU shop makes aprons; Mrs. James Mitchell pours for participants; exhibit of a start-of-the-century sweatshop with boss; participants with VP Angela Bambace-5/1/60; VP Angela Bambace with Of Halm at the Ghana Embassy; ILGers march in parade; ILGWU union label tent at a fair in DuQuoin, IL- with Helen Robinett, Leon Williams, Mae Chambers, and Mildred Wade; John Gelo- assistant director of label department with Min Matheson- director; union label float in a parade- with ILGers on board; Mrs. Nelson Rockefeller takes needle from David Dubinsky and sews first label- 1/15/59; ILGWU participate in the Easter Parade; Governor David Lawrence and union label director Michael Johnson-7/1/60; union label director vice president Julius Hochman; President Meany wears ILGWU apron with Marta Acosta, Blanca Valdes, Oneida Rodriguez, Margarita Alamequer- Local 415-3/1/61; At local 105, Ben Lord- president of Lortogs Co, Abe Dolgin- manager of Cutter's Local 10, Joe Rubin- executive director of employers association, ILGWU David Dubinsky and Mrs. George Meany- 6/15/61; Local 400 members aboard a float through Roanoke, VA- 12/15/61; Cleveland Knitgoods Council and Cleveland Joint Board participate in parade as Easter bunnies- 5/1/62; Mamie Zxner demonstrates sewing technique to Dorothy Kaufman of Central States Union Label staff, US Secretary of Labor W. Willard Wirtz, VP Frederick Siems, President Meany- 6/15/63; union label woman wearing label dresses pose; ILGers Rose Weisberger and Stephen Lewin show LBJ monogram- 8/15/64; Shari Belafonte wearing union label apparel- 12/1/63; union label fashion show; Union Label Director Min Matheson 5/1/68; President Eisenhower and President Meany
- Union Label Dept., Black and white photograph; Color photograph (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Unity House digital photos (Box 24, Folder 5)
  Includes: portrait of people relaxing on lawn on unity house; VP Gerald Grossman talks with cutters who participated in Cloak Dress Joint Board seminar at Unity House- 6/3/81; a couple sitting on the docks at Unity House; people rowing on the lake
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 25)